Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults (CSLEA) Records
Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults (CSLEA) Records
- Publication files
  - Macmillan-CSLEA Adult Education Series, 1961 (Box 68)
  - Memoranda re publications, 1951-1967 (Box 69)
  - News items for the AUEC Newsletter, 1961-1965 (Box 69)
  - Newsletter
    - 1957-1964 (Box 69)
    - Clearinghouse Bulletin, 1958-1960 (Box 69)
    - Continuing Education for Adults
      - 1961-1963 (Box 69)
      - 1964-1968 (Box 69)
    - Pattern and innovation, 1967-1968 (Box 69)
  - Publication lists, 1952-1964 (Box 69)
  - Publication schedules, 1960-1965 (Box 69)
  - Publications Committee meetings, 1954-1964 (Box 69)
  - Publications Committee reports, 1955-1956 (Box 69)
- Writings
  - Addresses
    - Bacon, Emery F.
      - Achieving Excellence in Labor Education, 1959 Nov 20 (Box 70)
    - Beirne, Joseph A.
      - Remarks at CWA Staff Trainee Program, 1961 Oct 1 (Box 70)
    - Blakely, Robert J.
      - Adult Education in and for a Free Society, 1952 Oct 20 (Box 70)
      - Adult Education, For What?, 1959 Mar 9 (Box 70)
      - The Educative Role of the Labor Leader, 1966 Jun 4 (Box 70)
    - Byrd, Robert C.
      - How Can the American University Reach out to the Nation's Capital?, 1965 May 15 (Box 70)
    - Coombs, Philip H.
      - The University and Its External Environment, undated (Box 70)
    - Demerath, Nicholas J.
      - The Changing Character of the University, 1959 Mar 5 (Box 70)
    - Diekhoff, John S.
      - The Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1951 Jul (Box 70)
      - The Domain of the Evening College Faculty, undated (Box 70)
    - Golden, Clinton S.
      - The American Trade Union Movement, 1959 Jun 23 (Box 70)
    - Haygood, Kenneth
      - Remarks at AUEC Convention, 1964 Oct 27 (Box 70)
    - Johnson, Earl S.
      - Some Reflections on the Meaning of Work, 1963 Mar (Box 70)
    - Liveright, Alexander A.
      - Advances in the Development of Professional Education of Adult Educators, 1958 (Box 70)
      - New Directions in Liberal Adult Education, 1958 Apr 20 (Box 70)
      - Liberal Education Defined and Illustrated, 1958 Nov 17 (Box 70)
      - Adult Education in the Daring Sixties, 1959 (Box 70)
      - Remarks to Graduates, University High School, 1959 Jun 11 (Box 70)
      - Continuing Adult Education: A Challenge in the Liberal Arts, 1959 Sep 17 (Box 70)
      - Liberal Adult Education--For Today and Tomorrow, 1959 Oct 1 (Box 70)
      - Leadership for What, 1960 Oct 10; outline (Box 70)
      - National Trends in Higher Adult Education, 1960 Nov 10 (Box 70)
      - Shape of the Future in Continuing Education, 1961 Feb 11 (Box 70)
      - The First Commencement, or There are Still Frontiers in Oklahoma, 1961 Mar 18 (Box 70)
      - University Adult Education, The Center of Experiment in Education, 1961 May (Box 70)
      - The Role of the University in an Undirected Society, 1961 Jun 12 (Box 70)
      - Finding and Developing Hidden Potentials, 1961 Oct 4 (Box 70)
      - Report of the Center, 1961 Nov 6 (Box 70)
      - Evaluation: Its Relationship to Research in Adult Education, 1961 Dec 1 (Box 70)
      - Creativity in Programming, 1962 Mar 26 (Box 70)
      - New Directions in University Programming for Adults, 1961 Apr 3 (Box 70)
      - Continuing Education: An Essential for Competence and Fulfillment, 1962 Jul 11 (Box 70)
      - New Horizons for Liberal Adult Education, 1962 Dec (Box 70)
      - Remarks at CSLEA-CADESS Meeting, 1963 (Box 70)
      - "Aging and Social Policy: Liberal and Avocational Education", 1963 Jun (Box 70)
      - Formal and Informal Adult Education, 1963 Jul 16 (Box 70)
      - Modifications in Credit Systems of Other Universities, 1964 Jun (Box 70)
      - A University for Adults in a Learning Society, 1964 Sep 21 (Box 70)
      - Role of the University in Continuing Education, 1964 Oct 16 (Box 70)
      - Toward the New Learning Society, 1965 Nov 30 (Box 70)
      - Identification and Development of Leadership, 1966 Jan 18 (Box 70)
      - Order Out of Chaos: Toward a Sound Program of Comprehensive Continuing Education in the United States, 1966 Feb 11 (Box 70)
      - Nature and Aim of Adult Education, 1966? Mar 24 (Box 70)
      - University Extension, A Function of the Modern University, 1966 Apr 14 (Box 70)
      - Continuing Education in the Modern City, 1966 Apr 20 (Box 70)
      - Trends in University Adult Education, 1966 Jul 6 (Box 70)
      - The Urban Condition: The Stakes of the University, 1966 Dec 8 (Box 70)
      - Legislation for Social Change, 1967 Nov 17 (Box 70)
      - Liberal Education for Adults, 1967 (Box 70)
      - The Challenge of Liberal Adult Education, undated (Box 70)
      - Focusing Public Attention on Adult Education, undated (Box 70)
    - Long, Herman
      - Political Developments, undated (Box 70)
    - McConnell, Thomas R.
      - A Look at the Total Educational Scene, 1959 Mar 9 (Box 70)
    - McMahon, Ernest E.
      - The NUEA, 1964 Oct 26 (Box 70)
    - McNeil, Donald R.
      - A New Look at Some Old Friends, 1962 Oct 14 (Box 70)
      - Crises in University Adult Education, 1962 Nov 11 (Box 70)
    - Miller, Harry L.
      - Becoming a Profession: Its Problems and Rewards, 1957 Mar (Box 70)
      - Your Stakes in Adult Education, 1957 Mar 29 (Box 70)
      - No title, undated (Box 70)
    - Powell, John Walker
      - Remarks at the International Congress of University Adult Education, 1967 (Box 70)
    - Rouch, Mark A.
      - What Does the Minister Need for his Continuing Education?, 1967 Aug (Box 70)
    - Schwertman, John B.
      - Challenges to Formal Classroom Programming in Adult Education, 1953 Dec 16 (Box 70)
    - Siegle, Peter E.
      - Some Remarks on a Panel at the New England Regional Conference on Industry-Liberal Education Relations, 1957 Oct 20 (Box 70)
      - Kitch and U, 1959 Jun 11 (Box 70)
      - Remarks, undated (Box 70)
    - Spengler, Edwin H.
      - Bench Marks and Turning Points, 1964 Sep 26 (Box 71)
    - Theobald, Robert
      - Human Rights in a Cybernated Age, 1963 Dec (Box 71)
    - Thiede Wilson B.
      - The Role of the Extension Dean--Mobilizing the Faculty for Change, 1966 Jul 6 (Box 71)
    - Ward, Barbara
      - Forethought for Tomorrow's Needs, 1957 Mar 5 (Box 71)
    - Whipple, James B.
      - The Continuing Task, 1967 Mar 22 (Box 71)
    - White, Thurman
      - Professional Training for Leadership, 1962 Apr (Box 71)
      - The Dynamic Challenge of Continuing Education in the Decade Ahead, 1962 Apr (Box 71)
    - Winters, Clifford L., Jr.
      - Cooperating with Other Groups, 1963 Oct 27 (Box 71)
      - A Paradigm for a New Professional Association for Continuing Higher Education, 1964 Oct 26 (Box 71)
    - Wright, Marion A.
      - The Negro College and Adult Education, 1962 Jun 9 (Box 71)
    - Authors unidentified
      - Buddhism and Modern Science, undated (Box 71)
      - "College Life Begins at 40", undated (Box 71)
  - Articles and books
    - Barton George E., Jr. (ed.)
      - Education in New Perspectives, 1956; draft (incomplete) (Box 71)
      - Liberal Education in Perspective, undated; draft (Box 71)
      - "The Perspective of Method", 1954 (Box 71)
    - Blakely, Robert J.
      - Anthology on Liberal Education, 1964; draft (incomplete) (Box 71)
      - Toward a Homeodynamic Society, 1965
        - Draft A (Box 71)
        - Draft B (Box 71)
        - Draft C (Box 72)
      - "What is Adult Education", undated (Box 72)
    - Burkett, J. E. and Paul G. Ruggiers (eds.)
      - Bachelor of Liberal Studies: Development of a Curriculum at the University of Oklahoma, 1965; Draft A, Draft B, Proof copy and errata page; 3 folders (Box 72)
    - Cotton, Webster
      - Rationale for Adult Education in a Free Society, 1967; Draft A, Draft B; 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Crimi, James E.
      - Adult Education in the Liberal Arts Colleges, 1957; draft (Box 72)
    - Cummings, Thomas F., Jr. (ed.)
      - Anthropological Backgrounds of Adult Education, 1968; Draft A (incomplete), Draft B; 2 folders (Box 72)
      - Political Backgrounds of Adult Education: The University in Urban Society, 1967; Draft A (incomplete), Draft B, Printed matter; 3 folders (Box 73)
    - Daigneault, George
      - "Future of the Evening College", 1965; draft (Box 73)
    - DeCrow, Roger (ed.)
      - Growing Time, 1964; Draft A, Draft B; 2 folders (Box 73)
    - Deinum, Andries
      - Speaking of Myself, 1966; Draft A, Printed matter; 2 folders (Box 73)
    - Dickerman, Watson
      - "Another Pilgrim Consults the Danish Oracle", 1965 (Box 73)
    - Drucker, Peter F., et al.
      - The Oakland Papers, 1965; Draft A, Draft B, Draft C; 3 foldes (Box 74)
    - Getzels, Jacob W.
      - Learning Theory and Classroom Practice in Adult Education, undated; script of a film strip (Box 74)
    - Goldberg, Maxwell H.
      - Knowledge and the Whole Man, undated; draft; 2 folders (Box 74)
      - Meaning and Metaphor, 1965; Draft A, Draft A miscellaneous papers, Printed matter; 3 folders (Box 74)
    - Goldman, Freda H.
      - The Arts in Higher Education, 1966
        - Draft A (Box 74)
        - Draft B (Box 75)
      - "New Theater and Adult Education", 1965 (Box 75)
      - "University Adult Education in the Arts", undated (Box 75)
      - Women, Work and Education, undated; Draft A, Draft B; 2 folders (Box 75)
    - Gordon, Morton
      - Daytime School for Adults: A New Program Dimension at the University of California, Berkeley, 1967; Draft A, Draft B, Draft C; 3 folders (Box 75)
      - "University Level", undated (Box 75)
    - Havighurst, Robert J.
      - "Social Roles of the Middle-Aged Person", 1953 (Box 75)
    - Haygood, Kenneth
      - Developing and Administering Community Education Programs, 1960; printed matter (Box 75)
      - "Education for Urban Change", 1962; printed matter (Box 75)
      - "The Impact of Urbanization on University Extension", 1962; printed matter (Box 75)
      - The Informal College Program, University College, the University of Chicago, 1959; draft (Box 75)
      - A Live Option: The Future of the Evening College (ed.), 1965
        - Draft A (Box 75)
        - Draft A, miscellaneous material (Box 76)
        - Draft B (Box 76)
    - Houle, Cyril O.
      - "An Appraisal of the American Universities' Role in Adult Education", 1958 (Box 76)
      - Federal Policies Concerninq Adult Education, 1967; printed matter (Box 76)
    - Johnson, Eugene I.
      - Metroplex Assembly, 1965; draft (Box 76)
    - Kaplan, Max
      - The Arts for Free Time, 1965; draft (Box 76)
    - Kellan, Horace
      - "The Liberation of the Adult", 1954 (Box 76)
    - Knox, Alan B.
      - "Dimensions of Education", 1959 (Box 76)
    - Liveright, Alexander A.
      - Adults in College, undated; outline (Box 76)
      - "Conference on University Adult Education in Africa", 1962 (Box 76)
      - "Curing Ciardi's Ulcers", 1962 (Box 76)
      - "Degree Programs Especially for Adults", 1964 (Box 76)
      - "Education Beyond the Regular Schools", 1961 (Box 76)
      - "Extension Utopia", 1959 (Box 76)
      - "Informal and Continuing Education", 1965 (Box 76)
      - "Innovation in Higher Education", 1965 (Box 76)
      - Liberal Adult Education, 1961; draft outline (Box 76)
      - "Lifelong Education", undated (Box 76)
      - "Match the Role to the Task", 1959 (Box 76)
      - "New Institutional Forms", 1967-1969 (Box 76)
      - "The Scene in 1980", undated (Box 76)
      - "The Self-Educating Man", 1961 (Box 76)
      - "The Shape of the Future in Continuing Education", undated (Box 76)
      - Study of Adult Education in the United States, 1965
        - Draft A; Draft B, preliminary; Draft C, plus 1968 postscript, 3 folders (Box 76)
        - Printed matter (Box 77)
      - Study of Adult Education in the United States, 1968; Draft A, Draft B; 2 folders (Box 77)
      - "The Universities' Unfinished Business--Liberal Education for Adults", undated (Box 77)
      - "Who Are America's Lay Readers--What Do They Do?", undated (Box 77)
    - Liveright, Alexander A. and Freda H. Goldman
      - Significant Developments in Continuing Higher Education, 1965; draft (Box 77)
    - Liveright, Alexander A. and Noreen Haygood (eds.)
      - The Exeter Papers, 1967; Draft A, Draft B; 3 folders (Box 77)
    - Liveright, Alexander A. and Harry L. Miller
      - Leading Group Discussion, undated; 2 folders (Box 77)
    - McCall, B. C. and Peter E. Siegle
      - "The Learning Process", ca. 1959 (Box 77)
    - Miller, Harry L.
      - Participation of Adults in Education: A Force Field Analysis, 1967; Draft A, Draft B; 2 folders (Box 77)
    - Miller, Harry L. and Barbara Berger
      - Leading Group Discussion, 1954 (Box 77)
    - Montross, Harold W.
      - "Review of Adult Learning Studies", 1959 (Box 78)
    - Morrison, Philip
      - "Science: Promethean Hope and Despair", undated (Box 78)
    - Needham, Maurice
      - College Without Classes, 1961 (Box 78)
    - Neuffer, Frank B.
      - "Administrative Policies and Practices of Evening Colleges", 1953 (Box 78)
    - Neugarten, Bernice L.
      - "Personality Changes During the Adult Years", 1962; draft (Box 78)
    - Niimi, Violet
      - "Skeleton Outline of Points Which May Be Covered in the National Policy", 1957 (Box 78)
    - Ohliger, John
      - Listening Groups: Using Mass Media in Adult Education, 1967; Draft A (incomplete), Draft B, Draft C; 3 folders (Box 78)
    - Oleon, Sally J.
      - Changing Patterns in Continuing Education for Business, 1967; Draft A, Draft B; 2 folders (Box 78)
    - Pagano, Jules
      - Peace Corps Training: A Developmental Concept in Adult Liberal Education, 1965; Draft A, Draft B; 2 folders (Box 78)
    - Professors of Adult Education
      - Adult Education: A New Imperative for Our Times, 1961; final draft and printed matter (Box 78)
      - Adult Education as a Field of Professional Study, undated
        - Introduction, Liveright, Alexander A. (Box 79)
        - Chapter 1, Hallenbeck, Wilbur C., 3 drafts (Box 79)
        - Chapter 2, Verner, Coolie, 2 drafts (Box 79)
        - Chapter 3, Knowles, Malcolm S., 3 drafts (Box 79)
        - Chapter 4, Houle, Cyril 0., 4 drafts (Box 79)
        - Chapter 5, Liveright, Alexander A., 3 drafts, 1 galley (Box 79)
      - Fields and Methods of Adult Education, undated
        - Preliminary Outlines (Box 79)
        - Preface (Box 79)
        - Chapter 3, Knowles, Malcolm S., 2 drafts (Box 79)
        - Chapter 4, Liveright, Alexander A., 2 outlines and 2 drafts (Box 79)
        - Chapter 5, Whipple, James B., 2 drafts, 1 galley (Box 80)
        - Chapter 6, McClusky, Howard Y., 2 drafts (Box 80)
        - Chapter 7, Jensen, Gale, 1 draft (Box 80)
        - Chapter 8, Hallenbeck, Wilbur C. and Jack London, 3 drafts (Box 80)
        - Chapter 9, Essert, Paul L., 3 drafts (Box 80)
        - Chapter 10, Barton, George E., Jr., 1 draft (Box 80)
        - Chapter 12, Houle, Cyril 0., and Malcolm S. Knowles, 2 drafts (Box 80)
        - Chapter 14, Bergevin, Paul and John McKinley, 1 draft (Box 80)
        - Appendices material (Box 80)
      - Planning and Improving Programs of Graduate Study in Adult Education, undated; draft (Box 80)
    - Reed, Bernard and Peter E. Siegle
      - "The Future and Uniqueness of Evening College Programs", 1960 (Box 80)
    - Schwartz, ?
      - Self-Study Outline, ca. 1961; proposal (Box 80)
    - Schwertman, John B.
      - "Brief Factual History of the Center", 1956 (Box 80)
      - "Emerging Theory in Adult Education", 1953 (Box 80)
      - "The Purposes of the Evening College", 1953 (Box 80)
      - Writings, 1955-1956; printed matter (Box 80)
    - Sheats, Paul H.
      - The Need for Continuing Education, or the Case Aqainst the Adult Dropout, 1965; Draft A, Draft B; 2 folders (Box 80)
    - Siegle, Peter E.
      - College and its Community, undated; draft (Box 80)
      - The Continuing Task, 1967; Draft A, Draft B; 2 folders (Box 80)
      - "Counseling in the Evening College", undated (Box 80)
      - "Liberal Education for Adults", undated (Box 80)
      - "The Social Life of a Jewish Community", undated; abstract of a dissertation (Box 80)
      - "Something for Everyone," Vassar Institute, 1956; draft (Box 80)
    - Smith, Russell F. W.
      - "When it Comes to the Pooling of Ignorance", 1952 (Box 80)
    - Soloman, Daniel
      - "Teacher Behavior Dimensions, Course Characteristics, and Student Evaluation of Teachers", 1964 (Box 81)
      - "Teaching Styles and Student Achievement", 1962 (Box 81)
    - Spengler, Edwin H., Ernest E. McMahon and Clifford L. Winters, Jr.
      - Inter-Association Cooperation Reconsidered, 1965; printed matter (Box 81)
    - Stern, Bernard H.
      - "Adults Grow in Brooklyn", 1955 (Box 81)
      - "Never too Late for College", 1963 (Box 81)
    - Storr, Richard
      - "The Public Conscience of the University", 1955 (Box 81)
    - Theobald, Robert, John W. C. Johnstone, and Jack Weinberg
      - Perspective on Automation, 1964; Various drafts, Final draft; 3 folders (Box 81)
    - Torrence, Andrew B.
      - "Race and the University", ca. 1968 (Box 81)
    - Warren, Helen F.
      - "Some Thoughts on a National Policy for Adult Educatio"n, 1957 (Box 81)
    - Whipple, James B.
      - "Comparison of Academic and Business Perspectives", undated (Box 81)
      - CSLEA: A History, 1967; Draft A (incomplete), Draft B, Draft C, Draft D; 4 folders (Box 81)
      - "Degree Programs Especially for Adults", 1966; 2 drafts (Box 81)
      - "Democracy and Education for Public Responsibility", 1962 (Box 81)
      - "Master's Degree Especially for Adults", 1966; 2 drafts (Box 81)
      - "My Liberal Education Bias", undated (Box 81)
      - Purposes of the Evening College (ed.), 1967
        - Draft A (Box 81)
        - Draft B (Box 81)
        - Draft C (Box 82)
      - Review of J. A. Burrell A History of Adult Education at Columbia University, 1954 (Box 82)
      - "Southern Rebel", undated (Box 82)
      - Toward the Liberal Education for Adults, 1952-1958
        - Notes for a book, ca. 1968 (Box 82)
        - Rough draft, ca. 1968 (Box 82)
    - Whipple, James B. and F. Goldman, K. Haygood, and P. Siegle
      - Liberal Education Reconsidered: Reflections on Continuing Education for Contemporary Man, 1969 (Box 82)
    - Winters, Clifford L., Jr.
      - Dynamics of Change in the Modern University, 1966; Draft A, Draft B; 2 folders (Box 82)
    - Zahn, Jane
      - Creativity Research and Its Implications for Adult Education, 1966; Draft A, Draft B; 2 folders (Box 82)
    - Various articles, 1959-1968 (Box 83)
    - Author or editor unidentified
      - Book reviews, 1966 (Box 83)
      - Developing Critical Judgment, 1958; printed matter (Box 83)
      - "Education for Adults--Luxury or Necessity?", 1959? (Box 83)
      - "Education Outside and Beyond the Regular Schools", undated (Box 83)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 83)
- Micsellany
  - Bright ideas file, 1953-1962 (Box 83)
  - Brochures and announcements, undated (Box 83)
  - Cartoons (Box 83)
  - Clippings from periodicals, 1963-1968 (Box 83)
  - Log of institutional relations (Package 19), 1957-1964 (Box 84)
  - Memorabilia, undated (Box 84)
  - News releases, 1960-1968 (Box 84)
  - Newsclippings, 1951-1968; undated; 3 folders (Box 84)
  - Photographs, undated; 3 folders (Box 84)
  - Press releases, 1958-1968 (Box 84)
  - Reprints, 1952-1964 (Box 84)
  - UNESCO material, 1964-1967 (Box 84)